# Monu Raghav

Village-Shurkhuroo Post- Chandok , Bulandshahr Uttar Pradesh Bulandshahr, Uttar Pradesh, 203394 +91-9962727865 monuraghav@outlook.com

## Summary

Oracle Certified Senior Java Developer with 6.5 years of progressive experience in the IT industry, involved in complete SDLC including analysis, design, development, testing, implementation, support and maintenance of enterprise-level web applications using Java/Java EE technologies. Sound knowledge in Banking and card payments domain with leading clients including Bank of Ireland, Atos Worldline, BenefitWallet, A Conduent Product etc. as a Sr. Java Developer.

#### Education

**Aryan Institute of Technology**, Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

Graduated - August 2013

# **Employment History**

**NTT DATA Services**, Noida, Uttar Pradesh *Software Development Specialist* 

February 2019 - Present

- Responsible for requirement analysis of all the web applications and understanding the client requirements.
- Involved in estimating the tasks, code reviews, defect tracking and resolving technical issues.
- Involved in high level and low-level design of all the web applications and contributed towards detail design specifications for the web applications.
- Strong debugging skills, creative preparation of user-level documentation.
- Implemented rest web service using spring rest for Middleware service modules.
- Designed and implemented an application using JSP, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JSF, Spring Batch, Ajax, JQuery,
- Detailed hands on experience on tools like Jenkins, WinScp, JIRA, Confluence, Sonar, Putty, Postman, SOAP UI,
   SQL Developer etc.
- Integrated and modified software systems according to the end user specifications.
- Ex cellent customer service skills and positive attitude as demonstrated by receiving Sprint Super Stars in three consecutive months
- Having good hands on experience in version control like GIT, SVN, Clear Case.

#### Conduent Business Services India Private Limited, Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Senior Software Engineer

October 2017 - February 2019

- Execute and program on an application development team through all phases of the software development lifecycle
- Work alongside with other Senior Engineers to develop new J2EE applications in an agile software development team using scrum methodologies
- Works within established procedures to develop, test, implement, and maintain application software
- Participate in regular team reviews assessing each other's performance and helping to implement continuous improvement activities (Sprint Retrospectives)
- Develop close working relationships with members of teams within the organization
- Worked on technologies like Spring MVC, Struts, ibitis, Soap Webservice, SAML 2.0, Oracle and PL-SQL.
- Work with other technical contributors and Product Managers who challenge you to grow every day.

Software Engineer

- Under general direction, develops, codes, tests and debugs new complex software solutions or enhancements to existing software in a maintenance capacity
- Works with technical staff to understand problems with software and resolve them
- Forward thinking, independent, creative, self-sufficient and go-getter; who can work with less documentation, has exposure testing complex multi-tiered integrated applications
- May assist in development of software technical documentation
- May create optimization programs to resolve problems
- · Resolves customer complaints with software and responds to suggestions for improvements and enhancements
- Demonstrates broad knowledge of technical solutions

#### Novasys Consultancy Services Pvt.Ltd., Bengaluru, Karnataka

Software Trainee July 2014 - December 2014

#### **Hobbies & Interests**

- Volunteer at Conduent CSR group, which works along with NGO for Poor Children's Education.
- Participate in Tech-Forum conducted annually in Atos.
- Love to play Cricket.
- Volunteer to work with Innovation/Ideas Team in Conduent.
- Volunteer for many technical quiz and competitions.

### **Professional Skills**

Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Hibernate, REST, Expert

SOAP, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Javascript, React-JS, AJAX, JSP, PL-SQL

Tomcat, Websphere, Jboss, Jenkins, Advanced

Confleunce, JIRA, Agile Scrum Methodology,

Docker, Splunk, GIT, SVN

Ex cellent team building skills, meeting Advanced

preparation and organization

# Languages

English Fluent Hindi Native

#### References

Satvinder Singh
Atos India Pvt. Ltd

Solution Architect Pune (997) 010-1761 Pune

satvinder89@gmail.com

## Linked Profile

For more details, Kindly walkthrough on my linked profile:

linkedin.com/in/monu-raghav-b7509398